<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://igorcferreira.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://igorcferreira.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2026-01-28T17:17:13+00:00</updated><id>https://igorcferreira.com/atom.xml</id><title type="html">Igor Ferreira</title><subtitle>Um blog escrito por &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@igorcferreira&quot;&gt;mim&lt;/a&gt; sobre coisas</subtitle><author><name>Igor Ferreira</name></author><entry><title type="html">A change</title><link href="https://igorcferreira.com/life/2026/01/28/uma-mudanca/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A change" /><published>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://igorcferreira.com/life/2026/01/28/uma-mudanca</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://igorcferreira.com/life/2026/01/28/uma-mudanca/"><![CDATA[<p>11 years ago I was moving from São Paulo to London.
And 9 years ago I wrote the post <a href="/en/life/2017/03/28/so-long/">So long… Thanks for all the fish!</a>,
where I talked about my move from London to Barcelona.</p>

<p>Now, a new change is happening in my life. At the end of March, I say goodbye to <a href="https://futureworkshops.com">Future Workshops</a>,
a company where I’ve worked for the last 10 years. A decade that ends.</p>

<p>I say goodbye because the company has reached a point where I no longer identify with it. The projects, the clients, the challenges,
and the day-to-day are no longer the same. The strategy of investing in the Saudi Arabia market, and the consequences
of that investment, no longer make me comfortable being at the company.</p>

<p>At the beginning of this investment, I wrote the post <a href="/en/life/2020/05/17/assexualidade">Asexuality</a>, and the desire to write
that post came, in part, from the change in reality that is being involved in Saudi Arabian culture. For years I tried
to understand the consequences and what was happening, and in the last 2 years I tried to motivate the company to end/change
the relationship with the region. Now, it’s my moment to distance myself.</p>

<p>I still really like the people who work at the company, in London and Barcelona, and ending this relationship was
not an easy decision, since I would like to still work with this team. But, in fact,
it’s my moment to distance myself.</p>

<p>You, who read this here, and are not related to the company nor know the company, must be wondering: “And what does this have to do with me?”</p>

<p>My answer to you is: I don’t know.</p>

<p>I just wanted to write and publish my thought. Especially since, now, comes the biggest question: And what do I do now?</p>

<p>My job was a big factor for my staying in Barcelona. Living in Europe has great benefits.
But I feel alone. I didn’t make friendships outside of work, and my family is an ocean away.
It’s time to decide if staying in Europe is still an option. And even if I stay in Europe,
whether staying in Barcelona is a good option.</p>

<p>I believe I’ll write again when I’ve decided, but I wanted to write that I need to think.</p>]]></content><author><name>Igor Ferreira</name></author><category term="Life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[11 years ago I was moving from São Paulo to London. And 9 years ago I wrote the post So long… Thanks for all the fish!, where I talked about my move from London to Barcelona.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing from the past - Breakfast</title><link href="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/11/25/cafe-da-manha/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing from the past - Breakfast" /><published>2024-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/11/25/cafe-da-manha</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/11/25/cafe-da-manha/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.recantodasletras.com.br/contoscotidianos/3304201">29/10/2011 - Breakfast</a></p>

<p>He turned on the light out of habit for brightness. With dragging steps, he crossed the kitchen and opened the windows, letting the strong morning sun invade the space. He returned and let his hand fall on the switch, turning off the lamp without changing the brightness of the area. He stood still for a few more moments. His body and mind had not fully awakened and took every opportunity to stop and go back to sleep.</p>

<p>He gathered all the strength he had and prepared strong coffee. He went through the cupboards and fridge looking for accompaniments and fruits, and set up a complete and incredibly symmetrical feast for his breakfast.</p>

<p>He sat at the end of a long, wide rectangular table, with his back to the window so as not to blind himself with the light coming through it and to be comfortable. Besides, he enjoyed a nice breeze from behind and a pleasant counter-current of air caused by the nearby cupboards. He could still see all the other chairs. He was at the center and at the end at the same time. That was definitely the best spot.</p>

<p>Finally, he placed the cutlery carefully beside the empty plate and began to move and rearrange what was on the table to ensure symmetry. After a few minutes on the unnecessary task, he gave up and decided to start eating, even a bit unhappy with the color difference between the jelly and butter jars (which shared the center of the table). He served himself with the utmost care to maintain the position of things, relaxed, and let his mind fly with each piece of bread.</p>

<p>The memories, favored by the surroundings, took him to a Christmas party that had happened many years ago. This was still his parents’ house and he could indulge in the futilities of childhood. The rooms were full of relatives and friends eating and drinking and several children running all over. The pleasant traditional end-of-year chaos.</p>

<p>As always, he took care of realigning and redistributing cups, drinks, and sweets as they were consumed. The table (which now received his breakfast) kept the treats properly balanced and distributed, with the minimum of flaws possible. After all, he was still young, he couldn’t push himself too hard. If there were still this type of gathering at home, the organization would be perfect.</p>

<p>- A penny for your thoughts. - His déjà vu was interrupted by a sweet voice greeting him.</p>

<p>Standing at the door, a beautiful girl with brown hair and eyes stared at him. Her body was covered only by a short gray tank top and discreet panties, leaving her legs sensually on display.</p>

<p>- I just went back a few years in time.</p>

<p>- Hmm - The young woman mumbled, going to sit in the chair that was free right to the left, near the young man. - Nostalgia was never really your style.</p>

<p>- I see you don’t know me that well anymore. In the old days, you wouldn’t even need me to tell you what I was thinking.</p>

<p>- You pushed me away, made me distance myself from you. You believed the stories and advice from your family and stopped talking to me. It’s been many years.</p>

<p>- And I still can’t believe I’m seeing you again. I must be very desperate.</p>

<p>The young woman gave him an aggressive look, snorted, and stared at him for a few moments before gently placing her hand on the young man’s hand. He even thought about pulling back, but hesitated.</p>

<p>- A lot has happened. - the young woman tried to comfort.</p>

<p>There was much truth in those words. A lot had happened in recent days. The peaceful and sweet life ceased to exist and chaos took its place. Never had his mind been in such an intense whirlwind and things only seemed to get worse. There was no light at the end of that tunnel, only darkness.</p>

<p>Igor Castañeda Ferreira</p>]]></content><author><name>Igor Ferreira</name></author><category term="Pensamento" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[29/10/2011 - Breakfast]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing from the past - A crow once told me</title><link href="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/10/26/um-corvo-me-disse-uma-vez/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing from the past - A crow once told me" /><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/10/26/um-corvo-me-disse-uma-vez</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/10/26/um-corvo-me-disse-uma-vez/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.recantodasletras.com.br/mensagens/3220245">15/09/2011 - A crow once told me:</a></p>

<p>Study, laws, question, learn to go after the solution to your problems. Try to find the peace of your spirit in the fullness of resolution. But don’t lose yourself in yourself. Have fun, have and make memorable moments. Throw yourself into lost hours with “nothing.”</p>

<p>Have friends. Even if few. But true ones. You’ll realize that you’re nothing, nor anyone, without them. Know that the most important thing in life is knowing that those who love you are and will always be by your side. A motivation for all suffering.</p>

<p>Family is the ultimate happiness. Not just the so-called “relatives,” but all who make you smile with a simple memory or just hearing their names. You are not alone in the world. And it’s these faces that will embrace your heart in a tender feeling called longing.</p>

<p>Be humble, strong, hardworking, and dedicated. Altruism is what sustains a real society. Seek your tranquility, even if it’s immersed in chaos. Know that you will find happiness in love. And, for that love, give yourself, even if it hurts. You won’t regret having “lived eternity” in someone else’s arms.</p>

<p>Upon fulfilling such objectives, be strong. They will take advantage of you. They will make you suffer. Your trust will be broken and your heart crumpled like paper. Bad times will come! And, for sure, they will pass.</p>

<p>Finally, one thing I assure you: “There is no formula for happiness.” Thank God. This is because it’s in every moment, every second. In the eyes of the one you love, in the hug of reunion, in the tears of goodbye… It’s up to you to see it.</p>

<p>Igor Castañeda Ferreira</p>]]></content><author><name>Igor Ferreira</name></author><category term="Pensamento" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[15/09/2011 - A crow once told me:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing from the past - Homesick</title><link href="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/10/24/homesick/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing from the past - Homesick" /><published>2024-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/10/24/homesick</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/10/24/homesick/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.recantodasletras.com.br/contoscotidianos/3162190">15/08/2011 - Homesick</a></p>

<p>It’s very cold here. Much more than I imagined. I went out to get firewood early today and could barely cross the street without my nose freezing. It’s abnormal.</p>

<p>The children went on vacation yesterday. The streets are happy now. A bit of color runs through the white and gray. It seems like I haven’t seen the sun in months. It’s very nice to be able to watch so much joy through my window, with a cup of hot chocolate in my hands.</p>

<p>Although it only snows at the end of the day, it’s very windy. Many were the times I needed to leave the house with several coats, scarf, hat, and gloves. All this to protect myself from this cutting winter air. My colleagues have been mocking me for a long time. It’s strange to wear so many clothes like this.</p>

<p>Last year I was there, at the beach. Another world, which I now worship and desire. I really miss that hellish heat. My neighbors say it’s not that cold and that in July it’s very hot. It’s sad, it seems I’ll have to wear a sweater even in summer.</p>

<p>Now a bunch of gnomes are throwing snowballs at my window. I feel like joining them and fulfilling that childhood dream, but I’m too lazy to go outside. It’s a very dubious moment I’m living.</p>

<p>I’ve reached a moment where anything makes me remember home. A tree that looks like the one in front of the house. The song that always played on the radio there. The smell of feijoada… It’s incredible how the mind starts playing tricks when we’re homesick.</p>

<p>A few nights ago I dreamed I was landing in the city, hugging you, my parents, and my siblings. It was so real. I was very sad when I realized I was still in this empty bed. I miss you so much. It’s normal for me to catch myself thinking about our walks in the park.</p>

<p>I think you would love to be here. There are many trees. Everything is calm. The house is nice and the people are friendly. It’s a great place to be and live, when you have someone to share meals with.</p>

<p>I still have that necklace you gave me. I didn’t have the courage to take it off. It’s been with me all this time and brought me a lot of luck. I hope you’re rooting for me, praying for me, remembering me… That’s what makes me want to go to work in the morning, instead of heading to the airport.</p>

<p>Tomorrow I’m going to the neighboring town to visit a potential client. My boss arranged a car for us and said I’ll be driving it. Imagine the thrill of crossing unknown roads. It’s a prank for the “newly exported” (as they call it around here): take the boss, without a map and without a cell phone.</p>

<p>It sounds like a cheesy horror movie. Only without the girl to save and without the hero wanting to show off. Just a car headed through the snow without direction and without communication. The complete package of solitude. It’s really a good prank.</p>

<p>Behind this letter is a photo with a dog I found in the neighborhood. My newest companion during my stay. He’s beautiful. Maybe I’ll take him with me. See if the little one can handle the heat with so much fur. Yeah… I think that’s all for today.</p>

<p>Hugs,<br />Igor Castañeda Ferreira</p>]]></content><author><name>Igor Ferreira</name></author><category term="Pensamento" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[15/08/2011 - Homesick]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing from the past - A ball night</title><link href="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/13/uma-noite-de-baile/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing from the past - A ball night" /><published>2024-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/13/uma-noite-de-baile</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/13/uma-noite-de-baile/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.recantodasletras.com.br/contoscotidianos/3099766">16/07/2011 - A ball night</a></p>

<p>- Stop being silly and come here, girl. - Ordered the mother in a mix of impatience with curiosity and enthusiasm.</p>

<p>The daughter came out of the bathroom with small steps. Her long brown hair was held by a lilac band, but still flew loose with each step. Her white skin burned in a shy blush and her eyes looked at the floor.</p>

<p>When she raised her face and received the amazed look from her mother, she covered her face with her hands and let out a moan of someone about to burst into tears.</p>

<p>- Stop that, dear! You look beautiful. - The mother hugged her daughter and led her to a bench in front of a mirror.</p>

<p>That statement wasn’t unreal. The long lilac dress passed a few centimeters from the floor thanks to the high-heeled sandals, the black bodice tightened and accentuated her breasts, and a band squeezed her belly, closing in a luxurious and discreet bow on her back. Even lacking the makeup and final touches on her hair, the young woman (used to wearing jeans and t-shirts) already had a majestic and enchanting glow.</p>

<p>Her anxiety increased with every tick of the clock, her stomach hadn’t left her in peace for a long time, and her mother’s silly smile made everything worse. She must look ridiculous in that dress, but she liked it, which made her more nervous. It was a sign that she liked being ridiculous.</p>

<p>Foundation, mascara, eyeshadow, eyeliner, lipstick, and the picture kept getting more and more beautiful. The mirror seemed to frame a painting that was being worked on at that moment by a great artist. She wished her friends were there with her, it would be really cool to accompany this change in all of them, but she realized it would be even more fun to see the surprised faces when she walked through the doors of the ballroom.</p>

<p>- No mom, please! Leave my hair down! - She gestured in supplication. She looked very pretty, but she couldn’t afford to go out showing her ears, they were too ugly.</p>

<p>After a small discussion, the mother convinced her to at least arrange it in a more elaborate hairstyle. The anticipation made it seem like an eternity, but the result was glorious.</p>

<p>The lighter makeup brought light that, embraced by the hair color, highlighted the beauty of her thin and rounded face. Her beautiful eyes stood out from the harmonious ensemble with a youthful sparkle, as did the discreet smile that had come to her face and stayed.</p>

<p>The small discomfort, the fear, and the knot in her stomach returned when the mother clapped her hands and announced she was done. It was time to go down the stairs and be embarrassed by her father who, for sure, would be with the camera and would say something silly. But the worst would be having to put up with the pest of a younger brother who would mock her, even though she was fabulous.</p>

<p>On the way, she noticed that the stairs of the house were bigger than she imagined, they seemed to never end. Thousands of things went through her head. Giving up was the most recurring word, along with millions of flimsy excuses. Some were even good, but she was so nervous she didn’t even notice.</p>

<p>Upon arriving in the living room, the silence that followed was worse than any nonsense or joke. She needed to hear a sincere opinion and, more than that, she needed to hear that she was beautiful.</p>

<p>That was exactly what she heard, but it only made her blush like never before, increase her anxiety, and only manage to stay still because her legs didn’t respond (her wish was to run like never before, to where, she didn’t know).</p>

<p>The cause wasn’t the compliment, but the voice that made it. Her companion for that night was sitting in an armchair near her father, playing video games with her younger brother.</p>

<p>The young man stood up, buttoned his tuxedo, adjusted his bow tie, and approached to receive the girl. The mastery of the movement made him even more elegant and handsome, as if the light eyes, blond hair, and slender body weren’t enough.</p>

<p>Surely that would be a spectacular night.</p>

<p>Igor Castañeda Ferreira</p>]]></content><author><name>Igor Ferreira</name></author><category term="Pensamento" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[16/07/2011 - A ball night]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing from the past - Melody of an angel</title><link href="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/09/melodia-de-um-anjo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing from the past - Melody of an angel" /><published>2024-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/09/melodia-de-um-anjo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/09/melodia-de-um-anjo/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.recantodasletras.com.br/contossurreais/2986670">22/05/2011 - Melody of an angel</a></p>

<p>The theater stood in the middle of the city. The tall buildings, majestic and refined, surrounded that construction from the last millennium. Wood, scaffolding, and metal pieces covered its doors and windows, and its walls had their paint peeling and hiding the life that once reigned there.</p>

<p>For many years, people passed in front of the building and ignored it completely. Some generations held marches, protested, spoke, and were heard, but no renovation was ever completed. The few that started to be done were cursed with accidents and deaths.</p>

<p>Against the wishes of the big businessmen, the city kept the building’s facade and maintains it standing as a reminder of the years of glory of what was the greatest stage of all time, until forces closed its doors forever.</p>

<p>Many elders are still able to recount how the glorious flames danced in its windows while consuming everything and everyone inside. According to the newspapers, nothing managed to cross the portals and reach life since the statues that adorned the passages were the first to fall, placing tons of art in the paths of salvation.</p>

<p>Those who pass through the lively square in the dead of night are able to say they heard the singing of thousands of people claiming life through a harmonious and beautiful choir, accompanied by the beautiful steps of the old curtains that come out to the audience, having the wind as their dance partner.</p>

<p>On one of these nights, when the full moon reigned at night, accompanied by its stars, a young woman who had missed the chance to catch the last transport home decided to wait the hours pass reading at the door of the old mausoleum.</p>

<p>As so many others had reported, it took only twelve tolls of the bell for the notes to begin to sound and the leaves of the trees to follow their rhythm. At first, the innocent winds passing through there were blamed for the melody, but it soon became clear that they contributed nothing to the phenomenon.</p>

<p>The girl, enchanted by the sound reaching her ears, closed her books along with her eyes and traveled in the suffering that allegro brought to her heart, while at the same time filling her soul with calm and radiance.</p>

<p>At the entrance of the second movement, a cello joined, removing the voices from the a cappella art, inserting them into a magical and morbid duet. The listener’s mind added violins, horns, trumpets, and oboes to the music, completing a glorious and false symphony.</p>

<p>While reason forced the opposite movement, the young woman’s body followed into the interior of the great stone monument, even without knowing the way. Her curiosity could not be contained before the fear of the unknown.</p>

<p>Inside, the scene was supernatural. Candles hung on glorious copper chandeliers were lit on the wall, and the ceiling shone with the help of a majestic crystal chandelier hanging by strong chains of the strongest iron. The antechamber, empty and enchanted with the most beautiful carpets, enchanted with a brightness invisible to its exterior.</p>

<p>Continuing, the vision was even more majestic. In the main room, the boxes leapt glamorous, living above the seats of the most beautiful red wool that contrasted with the oak that completed the seats. In them, several people sang with tuned voices, accompanied by the maestro playing at center stage.</p>

<p>The young woman knew it was impossible for a wooden object to sound with such force to fill the place with such vivacity, but the reality of the moment made everything seem real and plausible. Even more so when she glimpsed who moved the strings with such skill.</p>

<p>A tall and strong man covered part of the instrument with his long, straight, and black hair. His face was white, well-defined, and young. He was dressed in a smooth, beautiful, and well-tailored tuxedo that showed no resistance to the movements of his arms.</p>

<p>His gaze invited one to approach, something that was respected. The closer she got, everything around was disappearing and existence was limited to that being and the sounds that were born in his hands.</p>

<p>All the magic of the event was completed when the concert ended. Saying goodbye to an audience that stood up to recite the heroic finale, the musician rose from his seat while opening glorious and beautiful white wings that filled the stage with peace, calm, and happiness.</p>

<p>The applause of the ghosts that filled the audience made the conductor say goodbye to his listener with a look of gratitude and disappear covering his body through the feathered structure that leapt from his back.</p>

<p>The noise of the large book hitting the floor made the girl wake from the most beautiful dream and find herself trapped inside an old building, consumed by flames and abandoned by time.</p>

<p>The disappeared seats were marked by rotting and charred bodies. The walls were black from smoke and were falling from lack of strength. The stage only existed thanks to its strong metal roots, and the main chandelier lay within it.</p>

<p>Scared and confused, she ran, wishing for life, wishing for presence, wishing to feel she could still walk as mortal. Upon crossing a small gap that freed her from that cemetery, she saw the sun welcoming her to the world she knew. She could finally catch the bus home and survive among her loved ones.</p>

<p>The theater was still dead among the modernity that had risen around it, but the young woman never passed by there again without wishing and without fearing, longing to hear that beautiful sound played by the most beautiful creature and accompanied by the most wretched souls.</p>

<p>Igor Castañeda Ferreira</p>]]></content><author><name>Igor Ferreira</name></author><category term="Pensamento" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[22/05/2011 - Melody of an angel]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing from the past - Happy hug day</title><link href="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/08/feliz-dia-do-abraco/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing from the past - Happy hug day" /><published>2024-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/08/feliz-dia-do-abraco</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/08/feliz-dia-do-abraco/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.recantodasletras.com.br/frases/2986393">22/05/2011 - Happy hug day</a></p>

<p>In a hug, two hearts come together to vibrate in the same rhythm.
It’s a moment where two souls truly share the same body, the same feeling, the same experience.
Undeniable connection between any human being, sometimes feared, but always adored by those who suffer and by those who love.</p>

<p>Igor Castañeda Ferreira</p>]]></content><author><name>Igor Ferreira</name></author><category term="Pensamento" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[22/05/2011 - Happy hug day]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing from the past - In the morning, an accident</title><link href="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/06/na-manha-um-acidente/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing from the past - In the morning, an accident" /><published>2024-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/06/na-manha-um-acidente</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/06/na-manha-um-acidente/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.recantodasletras.com.br/contos-de-amor/2970284">14/05/2011 - In the morning, an accident</a></p>

<p>In the morning, an accident</p>

<p>The day dawned like any other.
Black clouds hid the sun behind a cold breeze and a light drizzle that invited workers to
hide in their homes or coats.
Several cars lined up in a procession through the asphalt and umbrellas floated along accompanied
by solitude and individuality.</p>

<p>In one of the cars, the sound system emitted a light and melodic baroque music that reached the ears of a young man,
accompanied by the honking of motorcycles.
A cigarette was being consumed, held very carelessly out the open window, and the driver accelerated and
braked following traffic automatically,
as if the body knew what to do without the need for the mind to intervene in such actions.</p>

<p>The typical commute to work was already stretching longer than normal, but this wasn’t even close to causing
any worry for Carlos, who was traveling in his thoughts that went far beyond that congested road
or the immense buildings that bordered it.</p>

<p>It was even a surprise and somewhat annoying when the car started moving faster after passing a construction site in the middle of the lane.
Now attention was focused on what was happening ahead, but his mind still came and went occasionally.</p>

<p>His distraction was accentuated by the change of music on the radio. Now the rhythm of the symphony made the steering wheel the
target of rhythmic blows and a humming accompanied by whistles emerged and took over the entire vehicle.
He even looked at the street clock, but didn’t notice he was absurdly late.</p>

<p>At the moment the orchestra was preparing for the presentation of the second theme, the young man’s attention returned due to a dull thud
and a strong jolt. Just to clear his soul of guilt, Carlos raised his eyes and saw the red light guiding drivers,
it wasn’t him who was wrong, a good sign.</p>

<p>Upon getting out of the car, he forgot for a few seconds why he was there and flew to a past that never existed and
to a future still being built, all because of a face, an image that came before him
and touched his heart like no other image could.</p>

<p>No one will ever be able to explain why or how this happened,
the sequence of events contributed to a completely different path, but Carlos didn’t worry,
he just enjoyed a wonderful day in the company of one of the most beautiful figures he had ever seen.</p>

<p>Both talked and laughed about the accident, the traffic, and the complication they caused, the delay and confusion with the tow trucks, and
even the fact of being forced to return home on foot that afternoon,
neither of them even remembering that they hadn’t gone to work, just enjoying the pause in a dry and sheltered bar.</p>

<p>The rain, the noise of people, the waiter offering another beer, nothing made the young man take his eyes off the beautiful
figure on the other side of the table. She was a redhead, brown eyes, young, cheerful, somewhat absent-minded, and youthful.
Her unpreparedness to deal with certain situations (traffic accidents especially) only took her one more step
toward perfection for the simple human who admired her and happily opened a silly smile every time his companion
gifted him with a look.</p>

<p>This moment stretched for a long time, but it happened before the clock caught its breath to move its hands and
only ended with the most irritating cell phone ring in the world at that moment.
Júlia was receiving a call from her boss asking if everything was okay and inquiring about her absence.
Life always tries to show you that your existence is insignificant,
but remember that your soul is immeasurable and even the universe can be small next to a being completed by the presence
of those one loves.</p>

<p>Both, after much negotiation, managed to get excused from work (a traffic accident shakes anyone’s emotions),
they went to the movies to watch an action and comedy film,
left very happy to have chosen the new animation that had just premiered and went to lunch.
Even with much reluctance and constant discussion,
Carlos always paid the bills and promised that he would let the girl pay the next one.</p>

<p>The afternoon was blessed with a shy sun among the clouds and a discussion about literary works in front of
a bookstore window in the mall. With some disagreements, each completely agreed with the other’s criticisms
and the conversation kept getting more and more pleasant.</p>

<p>A majestic full moon appeared to warn passersby that this day, despite reluctance, should end.
But a cycle had to close, interrupting a moment of wonderful peace and satisfaction and storing it in the safest vault,
memory. With a promise to see each other again, each took a taxi and went their way, with immeasurable happiness in their hearts,
accompanied by the hope of hearing the phone ring,
without realizing they hadn’t exchanged phone numbers or any other form of communication.</p>

<p>Igor Castañeda Ferreira</p>]]></content><author><name>Igor Ferreira</name></author><category term="Pensamento" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[14/05/2011 - In the morning, an accident]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing from the past - I would like</title><link href="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/05/eu-gostaria/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing from the past - I would like" /><published>2024-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/05/eu-gostaria</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/05/eu-gostaria/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.recantodasletras.com.br/mensagensdeamor/2925294">23/04/2011 - I would like…</a></p>

<p>“I would like to be able to apologize, say thank you, and proclaim to the seven winds what my heart has carried for so long.
Could I gather enough courage to put my soul at risk and look into your beautiful eyes while
I free myself from this weight that consumes me? I’m sorry for saying what I said and doing what I did,
but turning myself into a monster to your senses was the best way to push you away from my eyes,
since I will never be able to push you away from my thoughts.”</p>

<p>Igor Castañeda Ferreira</p>]]></content><author><name>Igor Ferreira</name></author><category term="Pensamento" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[23/04/2011 - I would like…]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Writing from the past - A morning</title><link href="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/04/uma-manha/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writing from the past - A morning" /><published>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/04/uma-manha</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://igorcferreira.com/pensamento/2024/09/04/uma-manha/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.recantodasletras.com.br/contos-de-amor/2898713">09/04/2011 - A morning</a></p>

<p>The electronic clock lit up at seven o’clock and started playing a strange song about the woes of those who suffer. In the chair beside it, a man was posted in his formal attire, accompanied by an empty whiskey bottle and a full glass that rested in his hand, forgotten by his own body.</p>

<p>He got up, placed the glass on the table next to the clock, capped it, and picked up the bottle. “A beautiful night, my dear Johnny.” He went to the window, opened the old cloth curtain, and saw the great light of the sun beginning to cover the city waking up for another day of hustle.</p>

<p>- Yeah. Looks like this starts again.</p>

<p>He took a few steps back and threw the bottle as far as he could. He still stood for a few seconds waiting to hear the sound of glass shattering twenty floors below, but when nothing happened, he snorted in compliance and returned to the room to reconnect the phone he had disconnected a few hours before.</p>

<p>As soon as the plug finished being inserted into the wall, a red light blinked on a button on the device. Upon pressing it, a mechanized voice extended in information about numbers and dates. Soon after, a slightly hoarse and familiar voice took over.</p>

<p>- Hey. What’s up, man? It’s me, Luiz. Are you there? I can’t reach you on your cell. Call me.</p>

<p>A beep, again the mechanized voice and a new message.</p>

<p>- Man, I’m worried about you. Ana said she saw you leaving a little after the speech. You should be home by now, call me. (beep)</p>

<p>- Hey, I’m downstairs and the doorman doesn’t want to let me in. Show up, let me come up. I know you need to talk to someone. (beep)</p>

<p>- It’s no use closing yourself off now. What happened, happened, there’s no going back. We should go out now, talk, complain, curse so we can laugh again. Sitting there alone isn’t worth it… (beep)</p>

<p>- As I was saying, it’s a great injustice, you and that black label there alone. I know you must have only the dregs left, but it’s always bad not being able to toast a label. I know a place you’ll love. No joke. Remember Evan… (beep)</p>

<p>- Remind me after I get you a new phone. This answering machine of yours gets on my nerves. I’m not going to try to get you out of the house, but use this time to think and, most importantly, forget. Sometimes happiness is in stopping suffering for what happened and paving your way in search of new events. Go… (beep)</p>

<p>He gave up standing there listening to the messages and headed for the kitchen. He grabbed a kettle from the cupboard under the sink and, in the most silence possible, filled it with water and put it on the stove. He heard noises in the hallway and saw a very poorly folded newspaper being passed through the mail slot in the door.</p>

<p>He collected that set of papers, opened them, and saw his photo stamped on the front page, just below a small text that said: “Young student shakes scientific community in lecture on the impact of manipulating basic life structures.”</p>

<p>He flipped through a few pages until he found the complete article, where a journalist with no knowledge of biology described how his speech had caused conversations, discussions, and even fights at the international biotechnology council.</p>

<p>This reading made a small smile appear on his face, but it was soon undone. It seemed that every small moment of calm or happiness made his mind conflict with his heart, bringing the pain stored in memories and driving it deep into his soul.</p>

<p>He noticed that the phone was still spewing messages from his friend and wondered how many more there were. He went back to the kitchen, searched for the coffee pot and found it dirty in the sink, waiting to be washed. He gave up on it, got a glass jar, the filter, coffee, and sugar and left everything ready waiting for the water.</p>

<p>With the coffee ready, he filled a large mug with the hot liquid, grabbed some cookies from a glass jar on top of the fridge, threw himself back in the armchair next to the phone, and busied himself making his stomach stop complaining of hunger.</p>

<p>He was finishing his coffee when the voice coming from the device beside him started to get annoying. He got up and headed decisively to silence the phone, but it wasn’t necessary. The metallic voice returned to inform that the memory was full and no more messages would be stored until action was taken.</p>

<p>Comforted by the news, he sat back down to have some peace before hearing the phone bell ringing insistently. He knew it must be his friend willing to bother again, so he let the device go to the answering machine. But the voice that came out of the phone was not exactly what he expected, making his body freeze and his chest tighten in a sweet pain.</p>

<p>“I understand you don’t want to talk to me, but I also know you’re there, posted next to that armchair of yours that you like so much. - Began a sweet and trembling female voice. - I probably won’t remember this tomorrow, so I hope it’s not being recorded on your answering machine and that you’re not listening. That bottle of champagne you left here is being very useful. It’s a very bad drink, but it helps to think. Very magical.”</p>

<p>“But I’m calling to be able to say what I really wanted to have said. You have no right to ruin your life because of me. It’s not fair! I have nothing but a mediocre life as an assistant in a mediocre office. Asking you to stay would be a very great injustice and I realized this watching your presentation today.”</p>

<p>“And I say this not only because of the many scientists who gave you a standing ovation at the end, but also because of the sparkle in your eyes while you spoke, the smile hidden in the seriousness imposed by the occasion, and the splendor of achievement and success that surrounded you. I can’t let you stop being this perfect figure just to make my heart feel the deepest joy of a fulfilled soul.”</p>

<p>“Now I’ve finished saying everything I had to say and, from the bottom of my heart, I hope you hate me in the same way and proportion with which I will always love you.”</p>

<p>- Hating you will be impossible. - The mug that once had coffee was in pieces on the floor and the phone trembled in his hand as he gathered strength to respond. - Every time I see a child’s smile I will remember the sweet pleasure of seeing you smile. Every time I feel the fresh morning breeze my heart will shrink with the memories of the best dawns of my life when I saw you in my arms. And greater injustice is to make two souls cry from a distance while a simple obstacle keeps them apart and suffering.</p>

<p>Both remained in absolute silence while small tears ran down the tired face of the young man who had his whole being focused on the search for his listener while the sun filled the room with welcome for another morning in the daily life of the lovers.</p>

<p>Igor Castañeda Ferreira</p>]]></content><author><name>Igor Ferreira</name></author><category term="Pensamento" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[09/04/2011 - A morning]]></summary></entry></feed>